Lure it to the village.
That's how we get the boss.
Wait, you can't be serious.
If we do, the boss will
go after the villagers.
Yes, that's the idea.
And while the boss is busy
killing NPCs, we can attack it.
And kill it.
But they're not just objects.
NPCs are different than rocks and trees.
Look, they're...
Do you think they're alive?
Really?
In this game, they are just objects.
And unlike us, if they're
killed, they can always respawn.
Sorry, but I'm not cool with that plan.
I'm running this operation, okay?
In case you forgot, I'm still second in
command of the Knights of the Blood Oath.
You'll obey my orders, like it or not.
Hey, what's with you guys? Huh?
You and the second in command.
You're always getting into
it, and not in the good way.
I guess we just don't click, eh, Giel?
You can become powerful here on your own,
but if the day comes when someone you
trust invites you to join a guild?
don't turn it down.
Well, she took my advice,
But who knew she'd join the top
guild and be a floor-clearing badass?
I want to always be with you.
I'll give you everything I have.
What are you doing?
Oh, hey. What's up?
Everyone in the assault team's working
their butts off to clear the dungeon.
And where do I find you?
Out here, taking a nap.
Even if you're a solo player,
you should take this more time.
I bet you didn't know this
is Aincrad's nicest season.
Today's weather is at its optimal setting.
Huh?
It'd be a waste to have to go
to work on a day like this.
Whatever.
I can't believe you.
Do you even understand what's going on?
Every day here is another
one lost in the real world.
Yeah, but right now, we're
not in the real world, are we?
We're alive in Aincrad.
See?
Doesn't that breeze feel good?
And the sun.
Oh, come on.
The weather's always the same here.
If you laid down on the grass for
a little bit, you'd understand.
Oh, damn, would you look at that.
Taking a nap in the middle of the day.
Some people sure got it easy.
Couple of lazy losers, man.
I can't believe she fell asleep.
It's here.
Good morning.
You slept like a rock.
You get one meal. Huh?
One meal.
All you can eat, my treat.
Then we'll be even. Deal?
that's asuna from the knights of the
blood oath really yeah they call her
the lightning flash who's the shady
looking guy dressed in black well anyway
thank you for today why for keeping
an eye on me oh sure the towns are
supposed to be safe zones and unless
you've agreed to a duel a player can't
attack or kill you but when you're
asleep you're vulnerable yeah now
we've got player killers who can cheat
the duel system duels are normally
supposed to be tests of strength not
a fight to the death but even if you
duel in a safe zone your hp is still
going to go down based on the damage you
take.
All a sleepy care has
to do is manipulate a
sleeping player's finger
to click the OK button.
The duel begins like normal, but the
sleepy care is doing all the attacking.
God knows how many
times it's happened.
So, anyway, thank you.
Sure, anytime.
Well, you'd do the same for me.
Hurry, pull it out!
I'll cut him down, you catch him.
Got it.
Help's on the way!
Damn it!
The only way he could have died in a
safe zone is if he was beaten in a duel.
That means...
Everyone, look for the
player with the winner icon!
There's no one here!
The room's empty!
So any idea how this could have happened?
Well, there's always the obvious.
There was a duel and the other guy
impaled the victim with that spear.
Then he put a noose around his
neck and pushed him out the window.
Wouldn't you say that's about right?
Yeah, but I couldn't see
the winner icon on anyone.
It had to be a duel.
It's a safe zone and a player died.
A duel's the only thing
it could have been.
Or maybe not.
Either way, we can't ignore this. I know.
As it is, a player takes huge
risks going outside a safe zone.
But if someone's found a way to PK inside,
No one's going to be safe
in the towns either, yeah?
You're right, I guess we.
Won't be going back to the
front lines anytime soon.
Listen, you're going to work with
me until we solve this thing.
Until we do, there won't
be any time for napping.
Okay, okay, but you're
the one who is napping!
Listen up!
Did anyone see what happened
before that player died?
If someone did, please speak up.
Sorry.
I can imagine how frightened you are.
Could you tell us your name?
Sure.
My name is Yoroko.
Was that you?
I mean, were you the one who screamed?
Uh-huh.
I knew him.
His name was Caynz and the two of
us used to belong to the same guild.
Anyway, we came here together today.
We were going to have
dinner somewhere in town.
But we got separated in the plaza.
I looked around for him.
Then I saw him hanging
from that balcony and...
Was there anyone else up there?
For a second there,
I'm not sure, but I think I did
see someone standing behind Caynz.
And this person, had you seen them before?
Um, I know this is hard for you,
but think back and try to remember.
Could there be someone, anyone
with the reason to kill him?
Thank you for walking me back.
Sorry if it's out of your way.
No worries.
But we'd like to talk to you again
tomorrow, if you're feeling up to it.
Okay.
So, what do we do?
Simple.
We follow the only solid clue we have.
If we can find out where
that spear came from,
it might lead us straight to the killer.
We'll need to find someone
with an appraisal skill.
I mean, it's pretty obvious you
don't have one. No, I don't.
And neither do you.
Oh, and by the way, try not to be
so rude when you're speaking to me.
Oh, okay.
Should I call you Ms.
next time?
Second in command?
Lightning flash?
oh never mind call me Asuna
okay sure back to the appraisal
skill though do you know anyone
who has it hmm I've got a friend
who does she's a weapons merchant
but she's really busy these
days so I don't think she'll
have time to help us no worries
I happen to know an item merchant
who might be able to help
us out
thanks
my man come back
anytime yeah whatever looks
like you're still running all
the suckers down with those hard
deals of yours no way kirito
buy cheap and sell cheap that's
my motto i'm a businessman you
know that that's selling cheap
parts a lie though don't go
slandering my good name brother
what the hell has gotten into
you you're supposed to be a solo
player man what are you doing
hanging around with Asuna his
HP dropped a zero in a safe
zone you sure it wasn't a duel
well no one saw a winner icon
we can also rule out the murder
being asleep PK he was walking
with Yoriko before it happened
and besides his death was too
elaborate to be some random duel.
The PKer who did this had it planned out.
We're pretty sure of that.
And then there's this.
A player made this. Really? Who
was it? Can you tell? Grimlock.
Never heard that name before.
It's not one of the top
blacksmiths, that's for damn sure.
Far as I can tell, there's
nothing Special about this,
yeah, but it's something to go on, right?
MM—Hmm, is there?
Like an item name listed,
you'll love it: guilty thorn.
There's a name for you.
It kind of fits, though—don't you think?
Seriously, guilty thorn!
guilty thorn
Here goes.
Wait, stop!
What's the matter?
What do you mean, what's the matter?
Are you out of your mind?
That thing's already killed one person!
I know, but we need to find out what
this thing's capable of, don't we?
Would you stop being so reckless?
Egil, would you please
hold on to this for us?
Uh, yeah.
So, uh, Yoriko, we, uh, we were wondering
if you had ever heard the name Grimlock.
Yes, I have.
Actually, until a few months ago, he
was in the guild with me and Caynz.
Listen, we took the spear that
impaled Caynz to an appraiser.
We had him go over it pretty carefully,
and we found out Grimlock made it.
Can you think of any reason why you did?
Yes, I can.
I should have told you
everything yesterday.
It's just, I couldn't.
It's something I've been
trying very hard to forget.
But now, I have no choice.
I should tell you about
how my guild was destroyed.
When we formed it, Golden
Apple was the name we chose.
Six months ago, we killed a rare monster.
It dropped a powerful ring that
raised a player's agility by 20.
Some of us wanted to
keep it for the guild,
others wanted to sell it
and split the earnings.
We couldn't agree and in the
end, we put it to a vote.
It was five to three
in favor of selling it.
Our leader, Griselda, took it to
a large town on the front lines.
She was going to sell it to a
broker and was staying overnight.
We waited and waited,
but she never came back.
It wasn't till later.
We learned our worst fears had come true.
Griselda was dead.
To this day, I still
don't know how she died.
No one's gonna leave a safe
zone with a rare item like that.
Too risky.
You think someone could've
pulled a sleep PK on her?
Not if it was six months ago.
That method's still sort of new.
You're right.
But she wasn't a random victim either.
No, the killer was after the ring.
It has to be someone who knew she had it.
Which means?
The killer is one of the
seven others in our guild.
Yes.
We have our suspects.
Now we just have to figure out
who didn't want to sell the ring.
I doubt the killer waited till
after Griselda sold the ring.
She was killed before she sold it.
That's my guess.
Probably.
Tell us what you know about Grimlock.
Well, I guess for starters,
he was Griselda's husband.
Oh, but not in real life.
Just in the game.
Griselda was a powerful Swordsman.
She was beautiful and smart.
Grimlock was kind, and I can't
remember a day when he wasn't smiling.
They made a great couple and
got along as husband and wife.
If Grimlock is really the one
who murdered Caynz yesterday,
then he's probably going
after the three guild
members who voted
against selling the ring.
Caynz was one of the three who wanted
to keep their reign for the guild.
I was the other one.
Then who's the third person?
The other's a tank named Schmidt.
And he, the last I heard, is on the front
lines now with the Holy Dragon Alliance.
Schmidt, huh?
I've heard that name before.
He's leader of the defense unit
of the Holy Dragon Alliance.
He's an exceptional lancer.
Oh yeah, him.
Wait, do you really know Schmidt?
Well, I've run into him a couple
times while clearing bosses, so...
I need to see him right away.
Could you please take me to him?
If he's on the front lines, he
probably hasn't heard about the murder.
He needs to know before what
happened to Caynz happens to him.
We'll help you get in touch with Schmidt.
I know someone in the
Holy Dragon Alliance.
He'll help us out.
We'll visit their HQ.
Okay, but first we should make
sure she gets back to the inn.
Yoriko, you have to stay there, okay?
Seriously, don't go
anywhere until we get back.
All right.
Okay, so how do you think a murder
like this happened in a safe zone?
I can see three ways it could have.
Right off the bat, it's
possible it was a fair duel.
Or maybe someone took
advantage of a bug that
combines a bunch of
different kill methods.
Yeah, I can see that happening.
And the third?
Use something to bypass the
protection of a safe zone.
Some kind of skill or maybe an item.
No, on second thought, that
third idea is impossible.
What do you mean?
Because it's unfair.
I kind of hate to admit it, but it's true.
The rules of SAO are essentially
fair for every player in the game.
So there's no way the game would
allow murders in safe zones.
I see.
So that's what killed Caynz,
and you're sure about the
spear, was it really Grimlock's?
There's no doubt.
But then why would he wait
six months to kill him?
Unless, wait, could he
have stolen the ring?
Do you think it's possible
he killed Griselda after all?
Does Grimlock want to kill the three of us
because we didn't want
to sell the damn ring?
Is that why he's after you and me now?
Maybe Grimlock made the spear
for someone else from our guild,
and maybe they're the
ones who killed Caynz.
Or maybe...
Griselda's come back from
the dead to get her revenge.
A player can't kill another
player inside a safe zone,
but something else like a ghost could.
I couldn't sleep at all last
night, so I stayed up thinking.
It was everyone's fault!
Everyone in the guild is guilty!
Her blood is on all our hands!
Our fate was sealed
when that ring dropped!
We shouldn't have voted!
We should have done whatever
Griselda told us to do!
Grimlock was the only one,
the only member of the guild,
who said we should leave
the decision to Griselda.
You see?
He's the only one of us
who can avenge Griselda.
He's the only member of our guild
who has the right to avenge her.
You gotta be kidding.
You gotta be kidding. Why now?
After all this time, why kill us now?
You can't be okay with this, Yurko!
How can you accept being killed
over some stupid vendetta?
You gotta go!
Let's
go!
Thank
you
so
much for watching.
Thank
you
so
much for watching.